Fernando Guevara

User Experience and Interface Designer

ferguevara.com • hi@ferguevara.com • Linkedin • +34 69272-3175 • San Sebastián, Spain

Summary

For the last eight years, I've been building awesome software products and services hand-in-hand with developers and multifunctional teams across different industries. My approach is based on human-centered design and Lean/Agile methodologies; learning from users, validating hypotheses that work, and testing ideas as soon as possible. My objective is to create simple products that people really want to use.

Professional Experience

User Experience and Interface Designer | Acklen Avenue

Aug 2015 - Present

- Solve UX problems, such as usability or findability, using a creative approach.
- Perform concept, usability testing and gather feedback.
- Analyze and meet product and business specifications, as well as user expectations.
- Create interaction models and evaluate their success.
- Build wireframes and prototypes around customer and user needs.
- Create and maintain scalable design systems.
- Collaborate with other designers to implement attractive and functional designs.
- Discuss design ideas and prototypes with developers and stakeholders.
- Maintain clear and open communication across teams.
- Stay informed about competitor products and industry trends.

Quality Assurance Engineer | Acklen Avenue

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

- Reviewing quality specifications and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback.
- Creating detailed, comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases.
- Estimating, prioritizing, planning and coordinating quality testing activities.

HTML & CSS Administrator | Laureate International Universities

Apr 2014 – Jun 2015

- Conceptualizing creative ideas with clients.
- Testing and improving the design of the website.
- Establishing design guidelines, standards, and best practices.
- Maintaining the appearance of websites by enforcing content standards.
- Designing visual imagery for websites and ensuring that they are in line with branding for clients.
- Working with different content management systems.
- Communicating design ideas using user flows, process flows, sitemaps and wireframes.
- Incorporating functionalities and features into websites.
- Translate mockups into clean HTML & CSS code
- Preparing design plans and presenting the website structure

Web & Mobile designer | ferguevara.com

Apr 2013 - Feb 2014

- Design conversion-oriented websites for different companies.
- Create digital marketing materials.
- Design user-friendly interfaces for mobile applications.
- Enhance client's brand through digital solutions, understanding market needs

Education

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Graphic Design.

UNITEC University

Design Research

UXER School

Skills & knowledge

Research & strategy

Agile software development, Lean startup, Usability Testing, Google Analytics, A/B testing, Card sorting, Content Strategy, Information Architecture, Interaction Design, Product Strategy, User Research, Competitive analysis, Journey Mapping.

Design

Figma, Sketch app, Adobe Creative Cloud, Design Systems, Responsive Design, Principle, Adobe After Effects, Marvel, Invision, wireframing, Prototyping, Visual Design, IOS & Material design.

Development

HTML, CSS, SASS, BEM, Javascript, Github

Languages

English

Spanish

Licenses & certifications

The complete web development bootcamp - London App Brewery

Credential ID UC-87c16d40-1e58-46fb-a41f-c678b27bdb3e

Advanced Google Analytics - Google

Credential ID rfUrvZzIT-CCmFEk9MxMgQ

Google Tag Manager Fundamentals - Google

Credential ID zacJHN5IT1Ou4ecAAoo1Aw

Inbound marketing certification - *HubSpot*

Credential ID e4f1057c510d4aaf92b8a52a5a704771

Courses

Do product research: analyze the competition and interview potential customers - Openclassrooms

1 day MVP 2.0 | Go from idea to MVP in just 1 day - Udemy

Google Tag Manager Fundamentals - Google

Conduct design and user research - Openclassrooms

Learn how to learn - Openclassrooms

Manage creative projects - Openclassrooms

Product Design - Udacity

Speak in Public - Openclassrooms

Honors & awards

Best mobile app - americas.datafest.net

Nov 2013

GLOBAL AWARDS CATEGORY